Jonathan Young

626 626 0656 | jyoungo696@gmail.com | iterating.github.io | linkedin.com/in/iterating/ | github.com/iterating

SUMMARY

Full stack developer experienced in building web applications and solving business problems with an array of technologies including **Javascript**, **Node.js**, **GraphQl**, and **SQL**. I'm a self-starter and quick learner who's not afraid to learn something new and apply it to any given task.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (contract)

2024 - Present

LA Film Lab and Studio, Los Angeles, CA

Developed full-stack solutions with event-driven architecture using TypeScript, Vue.js, and Node.js with Supabase as the backend-as-a-service, delivering mission-critical features that drove operational efficiency and customer engagement beyond growth expectations for a team of our size

- Implemented a real-time pub/sub event architecture with SSE and WebSockets, enabling instant order updates across all platforms
- Built RESTful API endpoints that retrieves and updates order information between Square's e-commerce SDK and Supabase database, resulting in seamless order management
- Developed optimized kiosks with Vue.js and TypeScript with centralized state management for order entry that reduced process time by 25% and reduced manual errors
- Created database migration tools and stored procedures with Javascript and SQL, leading to successful database migrations

Web Developer (contract)

2023 - 2024

Greater Boston Snow Removal, Boston MA (Hybrid Remote)

Developed scalable web applications that transformed the company into Boston's market leader, growing from 4 to 80+ employees through coordinated dispatch and real-time communications

- Built location-based worker matching system using Google Cloud API and MongoDB geospatial indexing, improving service time by 40%
- Engineered SMS management functionality with Twilio SDK, allowing for coordinated dispatch and updates

Business Analyst / Operations Manager

2020 - 2023

Greater Boston Snow Removal, Boston MA

Managed multiple operations teams and implemented route optimizations that reduced operational costs by 25%

Leveraged Eyeel and SQL to create dashboards for KPI tracking and business intelligence, driving strategic

Leveraged Excel and SQL to create dashboards for KPI tracking and business intelligence, driving strategic decision-making

Applied operational optimization experience to enhance software decisions in subsequent role as Web Developer, creating scalable solutions based on real-world business processes

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Query Builder

Developed platform that enables data analysts and developers to execute custom queries and build analytics tools

- Implemented RESTful APIs for PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MongoDB databases, allowing
 efficient data retrieval and processing
- · Applied data validation and error handling for robust data processing

Placenotes

Developed location-based social platform enabling contextual note-taking and message delivery based on users' physical locations

- Engineered a high-performance data architecture with geospatial indexing and real-time updates using MongoDB, REST, and GraphQL
- Built end-to-end JWT authentication across React frontend, Express.js middleware, and API endpoints, allowing secure user access

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Typescript/Javascript, Node.js

SQL, PostgresSQL, MongoDB

Git, Linux environments, Docker, Bash

GraphQL, RESTful web services

Agile and Lean methodologies

EDUCATION

Per Scholas

2024

Software Engineering Intensive, GPA: 4.0

Intensive training in Javascript and MERN full stack development, achieving top performance (4.0 GPA)

University Of 2014 -Massachusetts Chan 2018 Medical School

M.D. Candidate

Developed clinical decision support tools and won American College of Physicians National Abstract Competition *Publications*:

- Pretending to Be the Great Pretender. ACP Impact, October 2016.
- A Chemokine Protective Shield for Islet Transplantation. Digestive Disease Interventions, Boston, MA.

Tufts University

2007 -2010

B.Sc. Magna Cum Laude with Thesis Honors

 Managed IT infrastructure as Computer Lab Administrator at Eliot-Pearson Children's School, later earning Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) certification



